Venkata Vamshi Gunji

Ph: 5597248466 Email: gvvamshikrishna@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/venkata-gunji/ | GitHub: https://github.com/vamshigunji183

Career Profile:

Junior data scientist with 3+ years' experience, as a data analytics for Educational Service startup company and as a software developer, and research assistant for the research funded by the National Science Foundation, USA.

Core Competencies includes research, design, development, user data analysis, ETL pipeline, Data mining, database design, database management, Statistical analysis, Predictive modeling, Data visualization, and Report writing.

Experience:

National Science Foundation

A federal agency to support scientific exploration in Universities and scientific groups.

Research Assistant/ Software Developer

01/2018- Present

I am part of research team, responsible for research, design, and development of applications to investigate the applications of Mixed Reality technology in the construction industry conducted at California State University-Fresno.

- Developed speech-to-text application customized to on-site construction workforce as reporting tool, for mixed reality devices using Azure.
- Developed mixed reality application for the construction design review, resulted in improving performance metrics by 40%.
- Designed and developed virtual reality application for campaigning new university infrastructure, resulted in increase of students voting by 35% and raised funds over 3 million dollars for the project.
- Published 2 scholarly articles in esteemed scientific publications on topics related to mixed reality applications in construction industry over a 12-month period.

Talent Sprint

An Educational service startup company provides training and career services.

Data Analyst 04/2015-08/2016

Responsible for creating real-time dashboards using Tableau reports to identify and conducting analysis on company's key performance indexes, along with web scraping to improve the candidate's identification.

- Developed data visualization and analysis dashboard, optimized the data view that enhanced overall performance by 22% with the creation of real-time dashboards reports utilizing the data imported from Google Analytics.
- Developed automated process for web scraping from remote job posting for candidates' identification by 12% and create datasets to store in the database to produce the desired reports.

Education:

California State University- Fresno GPA: 3.3

2016-2018

Master of Science | Major: Computer Science | Research: Machine Learning, Mixed Reality

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University- India GPA:3.6

2012-2016

Bachelor of Technology Major: Computer Science and Engineering

Publication and Presentation:

Title: Closing the Skill Gap: Construction and Engineering Education Using Mixed Reality., 2018 IEEE

(https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8658992)

Title: Design Assessment in Virtual Reality and Mixed Reality Environments: A Comparison of Novices and Experts., JCEM 2018.

Technical Skill:

Programming: Python, C++, C#, Swift, Java, C, Shell scripting,

Statistical Analysis: R, MATLAB

Data Analysis: Pandas, Numpy, Scipy, Scikit-learn Visualization: Matplotlib, pyplot, Seaborn, Tableau Database Technologies: SQL, NoSQL, Hadoop, Spark Deep Learning: Tensorflow, Keras, Pytourch, Caffe, Thenos

Cloud Technologies: Amazon Web Services (AWS), Google Cloud Platform

PROJECTS

Spotify Users Churn Prediction

Analysis and predicting the frequency of users canceling the Spotify Premier subscription

• Implemented predictive model to classify the user to churn the subscription using gradient boosting algorithm with F1 score 0.62.

Tools and Environments: Amazon EC2, SQL, Seaborn, PySpark, Pandas.

NEWS Recommendation App

App recommends NEWS articles based on the history of people who shares similar interest.

• Built a pipeline to web scrape the NEWS article, extract features and offers recommendations using Latent Dirichlet allocation technique.

Tools and Environments: Google Cloud platform, Pandas, Scikit Learn, MongoDB, Python

NEWS Summarization App

An artificial neural network app to automatically reads a NEWS articles and suggests a relevant headline for the articles.

Implemented Reinforcement learning technique with an ETL pipe to web scrape the articles, clean and feed to LSTM-RNN architecture with bidirectional GRU.

Tools and Environments: Google Cloud Platform, Pytourch, NLTK.

Customer Segmentation

Bank's Client segmentation using unsupervised learning techniques.

• Implemented data pipeline to clean the data, feature extract using PCA and clustered clients using KMeans algorithm.

Tools and Environments: Numpy, Pandas, Sci-kit Learning, Seaborn

Predicting Bank Marketing Campaign Success

To predict client's policy acceptance and measure ad campaign success.

Implemented AdaBoost classifier to predict subscription with AUC score of 80%.

Tools and Environments: Sci-kit Learn, Tableau